https://www.girlguidingscotland.org.uk/privacy/

What we do
Rainbows (age 5-7)
Brownies (age 7-10)
Guides (age 10-14)
Rangers (age 14-18)
What we do
Rainbows (age 5-7)
Brownies (age 7-10)
Guides (age 10-14)
Rangers (age 14-18)
Privacy
We all give our personal data out daily – our names, contact details, or other bits of information – and most of us want to be feel sure that our data is being handled properly.
As someone who is in contact with Girlguiding Scotland, you may have given us information about yourself, like your name, or email address, or other details. Our privacy notice explains what Girlguiding Scotland does with this information – it tells you how we gather, use, disclose and manage your personal data.
We take your privacy very seriously. We aim always to be clear to you about the way Girlguiding Scotland manages data, so we make sure our privacy notice is up to date. You should read this page from time to time to check that you are happy with any changes we make.
Our privacy notice is as comprehensive as possible, but it doesn’t cover every aspect of our collection and use of personal data. Please contact us if you need more information, or have any questions about this notice. Our contact details are in the ‘get in touch’ section below.
What do: ‘Girlguiding’, Girlguiding Scotland’, ‘we’ or ‘us’ refer to?
“Girlguiding Scotland”, “Us”, “We” or “Our” refers to the registered charity The Guide Association Scotland (Scottish Charity no SC005548)
Our registered / Head office address:
Girlguiding Scotland
16 Coates Crescent
Edinburgh
EH3 7AH
In this notice we refer to “Girlguiding,” this is in connection to membership (GO) data. Girlguiding refers to the registered charity, The Guide Association (no. 306016 in England, Wales and Scotland. Girlguiding’s registered charity number is 306016 (England and Wales) and SC038436 (Scotland).
Get in touch with us
If you have any concerns about the Girlguiding Scotland privacy notice or about how we deal with data, or how we’ve used your data, please get in touch. Write to or email the data protection officer at:
dataprotection@girlguiding-scot.org.uk
The data protection officer
Girlguiding Scotland
16 Coates Crescent
Edinburgh
EH3 7AH
If your enquiry is about Girlguiding’s membership system (GO) and how they deal with data, or use your data please contact Girlguiding’s data protection team:
dataprotection@girlguiding.org.uk
The data protection team
Girlguiding
17-19 Buckingham Palace Road
London
SW1W 0PT
You can also make a complaint to the information commissioner’s office
Changes to this privacy notice
Keep up to date with changes to this privacy notice by checking the website section from time to time.
© Girlguiding Scotland
Girlguiding Scotland
16 Coates Crescent
Edinburgh
EH3 7AH
This privacy notice was last updated on 25 May 2018
What personal information does Girlguiding Scotland collect?
We collect the following personal information (where relevant or applicable):
Name
Parents’/guardian’s name(s)
Contact details, including address, telephone number and email address
Date of birth
Payment information (bank or credit card details) if you donate to us, make a payment for an event or buy from our online shop)
Records of your correspondence with us
Records of your participation with us (including as a member or as a volunteer)
Donation history and gift aid details
Information you enter on our website
Photographs, video or audio recordings
Biographical information
Information collected from your computer or mobile device (browser, IP address, geographical location, referring domain)
Any other information you share with us
This information may be collected from:
Girlguiding, via their membership system ‘GO’. Girlguiding Scotland has access to this data to use, amend, process and share. You can find more information about how Girlguiding collect and process your personal data in their privacy notice
Your computer or mobile device
Information you fill out on the website (via digital forms and online surveys)
Telephone or face to face conversations with you and/or your parent/guardian
Local or regional Girlguiding groups
Third party companies and websites, like Just Giving, Virgin Money Giving and Committed Giving
Publicly available sources
Hard copy forms
Communication on social media
We sometimes also collect sensitive personal data, for example information about health, religion, sexuality, ethnicity, political and philosophical beliefs and criminal records. We normally only record this data where we have your consent. But sometimes we are permitted to do this in other circumstances, under data protection law. We may make a record that a person is in a vulnerable circumstance to make sure that we don’t send fundraising messages to them – by doing this we comply with charity law and the Code of Fundraising Practice.
If you are 14 and under
If you are under the age of 14, you must get permission from your parent or guardian before registering or giving us any information.
Why and how do you use my personal data?
Data helps us support and improve interactions with Girlguiding Scotland. Examples include:
We use marketing materials for the following:
Updates about Girlguiding Scotland’s work, including newsletters and other publications
Appeals and fundraising activities including requests for donations; information about legacy gifts, raising funds or taking part in a fundraising event, and updates on the impact that fundraising activities have had on our work
Information about events
Information about shop products
Volunteering information about how to support Girlguiding Scotland, along with updates about the impact of your work
We may also use your personal information to build a profile of your interests and preferences. This helps us send you only relevant and timely information. And building profiles helps us improve the experience our supporters have – if we understand their background we can make appropriate requests to those who may be willing and able to give more than they already do. This helps us raise funds sooner and more cost-effectively.
There’s other information we can use, which is publicly available in places like public registers. This can include listed directorships, typical earnings in a geographical area, information from the electoral roll, press reports and social media posts.
Can I change my consent?
Yes! You can withdraw your consent, unsubscribe from or update your marketing preferences at any time. Just use the details in the ‘get in touch’ section.
If you make changes to your consent, we will update your record as soon as we possibly can. Emails will be stopped immediately, but it may take up to 60 days for our systems to update and stop post being sent to you.
If you tell us you don’t want marketing, fundraising or campaign communications, you may still receive messages about transactions and services from other connections you have with us (as described below).
When is it legal to use personal information?
We need a lawful basis to collect and use your personal data under data protection law. The law allows for six ways to process personal data (and additional ways for sensitive personal data). Four of these are relevant to Girlguiding Scotland. We can use process information on the basis of:
Your consent (for example to send you direct marketing by email or SMS)
Your contractual relationship with us (for example to provide you with goods or services that you have purchased from us)
The necessity for compliance with a legal obligation (for example to process a gift aid declaration and carrying out due diligence on large donations)
Girlguiding Scotland’s legitimate interests
What does legitimate interest mean?
Personal data may be legally collected and used if it is necessary for a legitimate interest of the organisation using the data, as long as its use is fair and does not adversely impact the rights of the individual concerned.
When we use your personal information, we will always consider if it is fair and balanced to do so, and if it is within your reasonable expectations. We will balance your rights and our legitimate interests to ensure that we use your personal information in ways that are not unduly intrusive or unfair. Girlguiding Scotland’s legitimate interests include:
Charity governance. This includes delivery of our charitable purposes, statutory and financial reporting and other regulatory compliance purposes
Administration and operational management. This includes answering enquires, giving information and services, research, events management, administration of volunteers and employment and recruitment requirements. This involves sharing information with regional and local levels of Girlguiding Scotland.
Fundraising and campaigning. This includes administering campaigns and donations and sending direct marketing by post (and in some cases making marketing calls), sending thank you letters, analysis, targeting and segmentation to develop communication strategies and maintaining communication suppressions.
If you would like more information on our uses of legitimate interests or to change our use of your personal data please get in touch with us using the details in the ‘get in touch’ section.
How long do you keep my data?
Girlguiding Scotland keeps your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
We decide how long is appropriate to keep personal data. We do this by considering the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data; the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data; the purposes for which we process your personal data, whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the legal requirements.
If you ask to receive no further contact from us, we will keep some basic information about you on our suppression list to avoid sending you more unwanted messages.
Do you share personal data with other organisations?
We do not share or sell your personal information to third-party organisations for marketing, fundraising or campaigning purposes.
We share your personal information with relevant regional and local levels of Girlguiding Scotland to:
Administer your membership of Girlguiding
Manage your participation in Girlguiding and Girlguiding Scotland activities
Conduct market research so we can improve our offerings to you and as an organisation overall
Conduct evaluations to improve the quality of our offering
We also share personal information:
With data processors working on our behalf. For example, if you buy an item in our online shop, we use third parties to host systems and to process payments
Where we are required to by law, for example to law enforcement or regulatory bodies
Where it is necessary to protect the vital interests of an individual
If we have your consent
We may use third-party suppliers to manage events, campaigns or mailings for fundraising appeals; to carry out research surveys or for storage of your personal information on our behalf. You can find out more about the suppliers that we use by contacting us using the details in the ‘get in touch’ section
How do you use cookies and digital marketing?
Cookies are small text files placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used to make websites work more efficiently for visitors, and to provide information to the owners of the site.
We use cookies to:
Remember certain information about users so they don’t have to give the same information again
Measure how people use our websites so we can improve the way information is provided
Display adverts based on what parts of Girlguiding Scotland’s websites people have visited
You agree to our use of cookies by continuing to use our websites. The Girlguiding Scotland website may share your personal data with remarketing services – including Facebook, Google Adwords and Google Analytics – to serve our adverts to you on third party websites. Third-party vendors, including Facebook and Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Girlguiding Scotland website.
Remarketing
The Girlguiding Scotland website may share your personal data with remarketing services – including Facebook, Google Adwords and Google Analytics – to serve our adverts to you on third party websites. Third-party vendors, including Facebook and Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Girlguiding Scotland website
Disclaimer
We cannot be responsible for any information you give in public community areas of the Girlguiding Scotland websites, or on websites that we link to from our platforms. This information can be viewed or collected by any third party – you should always be wary of publishing any personal information in public community areas.
You should also read the privacy notices of any other websites that we link to from Girlguiding Scotland websites which you visit. This is so you may understand what information is collected from you and for what purpose.
Girlguiding Scotland cannot be held responsible for the policies of any third party website that we link to, and you access these websites at your own risk.
We use cookies on our website to enhance your user experience. By clicking accept you agree to us doing so.
View more
Cookies settings
Accept
Decline
Privacy & Cookie policy
Privacy & Cookies policy
Cookies list
Cookie name
Active
We all give our personal data out daily – our names, contact details, or other bits of information – and most of us want to be feel sure that our data is being handled properly.
As someone who is in contact with Girlguiding Scotland, you may have given us information about yourself, like your name, or email address, or other details. Our privacy notice explains what Girlguiding Scotland does with this information – it tells you how we gather, use, disclose and manage your personal data.
We take your privacy very seriously. We aim always to be clear to you about the way Girlguiding Scotland manages data, so we make sure our privacy notice is up to date. You should read this page from time to time to check that you are happy with any changes we make.
Our privacy notice is as comprehensive as possible, but it doesn’t cover every aspect of our collection and use of personal data. Please contact us if you need more information, or have any questions about this notice. Our contact details are in the ‘get in touch’ section below.
What do: ‘Girlguiding’, Girlguiding Scotland’, ‘we’ or ‘us’ refer to?
“Girlguiding Scotland”, “Us”, “We” or “Our” refers to the registered charity The Guide Association Scotland (Scottish Charity no SC005548)
Our registered / Head office address:
Girlguiding Scotland
16 Coates Crescent
Edinburgh
EH3 7AH
In this notice we refer to “Girlguiding,” this is in connection to membership (GO) data. Girlguiding refers to the registered charity, The Guide Association (no. 306016 in England, Wales and Scotland. Girlguiding’s registered charity number is 306016 (England and Wales) and SC038436 (Scotland).
Get in touch with us
If you have any concerns about the Girlguiding Scotland privacy notice or about how we deal with data, or how we’ve used your data, please get in touch. Write to or email the data protection officer at:
dataprotection@girlguiding-scot.org.uk
The data protection officer
Girlguiding Scotland
16 Coates Crescent
Edinburgh
EH3 7AH
If your enquiry is about Girlguiding’s membership system (GO) and how they deal with data, or use your data please contact Girlguiding’s data protection team:
dataprotection@girlguiding.org.uk
The data protection team
Girlguiding
17-19 Buckingham Palace Road
London
SW1W 0PT
You can also make a complaint to the information commissioner’s office
Changes to this privacy notice
Keep up to date with changes to this privacy notice by checking the website section from time to time.
